S. Sadrul Hossain

Summary

Software developer and team lead with more than 4 years of experience. Sincere, hard-working and fast learner. Eager to learn new technologies, if necessary. Willing to build a sound professional career as software analyst with dedication.

Experience

October 2023– Present

Software Engineer

Daraz BD (Alibaba Group)

• Developing software solutions for internal use.

December 2022– September 2023

Software Engineer

PayStation (Service Hub Limited)

- Developing payment gateway APIs.
- Providing guidance to clients about payment gateway integration.
- Integrating bank APIs to payment gateway
- Developing PWA of mini-services

September 2019 - November 2022

Associate Software Engineer

Swapnoloke

- Performing as technical consultant in various projects.
- Managing multiple teams of developers for various projects.
- Planning work schedule and distributing work among team members
- Designing software process and modules according to client requirements.
- Designing process for complex modules of various projects.
- Preparing project documentation such as SRS, ERD, Use-case diagram etc. for various projects.
- Testing and evaluating works of team members.
- Dealing with clients as **first point of contact** in various projects.
- Mentoring junior and apprentice developers.
- Working as a developer in core and complex modules of various projects.

April 2019 – August 2019

Web Designer & Developer

Connect Bangladesh Ltd.

Responsible for maintaining all company websites.



Personal Info

- Flat#A3, Sixteen Holding, 322 Moynarbag, Sochib Bari More, Uttar Badda, Dhaka-1212.
- +8801885547800
- **f** www.facebook.com/sadrul.hossain.7
- in www.linkedin.com/in/s-sadrulhossain-71624aa6/

hossainsadrul@gmail.com

- github.com/sadrulhossain
- sadrulhossain.github.io/portfolio/

Skill

M

- Excellent analytical ability.
- Excellent problem solving ability.

Strengths

- Positive and fast learner.
- Sincere and hard-working.
- Loyal and dedicated.

Interests

- Camping and hiking.
- Singing and Listening Music.
- Watching anime and reading manga.

Language Proficiency

- Bangla High.
- English High.

Certificates

21 March 2019 Certificate for participation in

Workshop on

Hospital Management System **Provider**: SubraSystems Ltd. **Event**: BASIS SOFTEXPO 2019

Technical Expertise

- Strong understanding in PHP, OOP and Laravel.
- Expert knowledge in Vue.js, Vuex and TypeScript.
- Knowledge in unit testing with PHPunit and jest.
- Knowledge in cloud services such as AWS.
- Knowledge in MySQL, PostgreSQL and caching mechanism such as Redis.
- Basic knowledge in Python and React.
- Strong understanding in AJAX, jQuery, MySQL, JavaScript and CSS.
- Experience in Restful API and third-party API integration such as Facebook, Google, XPS Ship.
- Experience in Authorize.net and PayPal Payment Gateways integration
- **Experience in SMS Gateways integration**
- Experience in Payment Gateway APIs development.
- Experience in integrating Bank payment APIs.
- Experience in developing PWA using third party APIs.
- Familiar with shell script command line.

Professional Expertise

- Experience in developing projects single handedly and with team.
- Experience in leading 2-3 teams of different projects simultaneously.
- Experience in deploying projects and updates in Linux based server.
- Experience in interacting with high level clients and collecting requirements / feedback from client and converting client requirements into technical design.

Educational Qualification

April 2017 – June

Jahangirnagar University

2018

M.Sc. in Computer Science & Engineering

• CGPA 3.70 out of 4.

January 2013 -

Daffodil International University

January 2017

B.Sc. in Computer Science & Engineering

• CGPA 3.81 out of 4.

Notable Project Works

Assessment Software

- Performed as chief engineer in AFWC Assessment Software of National Defence College Bangladesh.
- Performed as software architecture designer and team lead of AFWC Portal of National **Defence College** Bangladesh.
- Performed as chief engineer and lead developer in SI&T Assessment & Management Software of School of Signal & Tactics Bangladesh.

Sales & Tracking Solution

Performed as team lead and lead developer in KTI - Sales & Tracking Software of Konita Trade International.

16 August 2023 – 18 September Arranged by: BITM

Cloud Journey with AWS: Beginner to Advance level

2023

Reference

Prof. Dr. Syed Akhtar Hossain

Dean, Faculty of Science & Information Technology,

Daffodil International University.

Moblie: +8801817382645

Email: aktarhossain@daffodilvarsity.edu.bd

Prof. Dr. Imdadul Islam

Former Chairman of the department of CSE,

Jahangirnagar University Moblie: +8801818729702 Email: imdad@juniv.edu

E-commerce

- Performed as team lead and lead developer in rebekasattire.com.
- Performed as team lead and lead developer in kingkiron.com of Konita Trade International.

Retailing & Distribution

 Performed as team lead and lead developer in d-retail.org of Arroz Limited.

Signature

(S. Sadrul Hossain)